Guide to the Administrative Files of the Dean of the School of Education, Daniel E. Griffiths 1948-1985 (Bulk 1965-1983) RG 26.0.1 RG.26.0.1
New York University Archives
Administrative Files of the Dean of the School of Education, Daniel E. Griffiths
1948-1985, (Bulk 1965-1983)
1965-1983
New York University Archives
New York University. School of Education
RG.26.0.1
160 Linear Feet 160 linear feet
This collection represents the administrative papers of Daniel E. Griffiths, dean of the School of Education from 1965-1983.
Arrangement
The files are arranged topically and extend to 160 linear feet.
Files are arranged into one series.
Missing Title
Inventory
Scope and Content Note
The files of the Dean of the School of Education, (renamed School of Education, Health, and Nursing Arts Professionals (SEHNAP) in 1974) date from 1960-1983. The collection reflects the philosophical and institutional history of the School of Education/ SEHNAP over two decades. The collection includes some material created during the tenure of Dean Walter A. Anderson; however, the majority of the administrative files were created under the deanship of Daniel E. Griffiths (1965-1983).
Subjects addressed in the collection include the School of Education's relationship to NYU, New York City, as well as to the greater United States and international community. The collection includes reports, minutes, financial records, manuscripts, correspondence, printed materials, and photographs. The files document educational and administrative issues that were of primary concern during Dean Griffiths' tenure, such as the introduction of new programs to the school, the examination of the doctoral degree programs, University Council for Educational Administration (UCEA) seminars (1959-1965), enrollment, and budgetary concerns.
Historical/Biographical Note
The administrative files of the Dean of the School of Education/ School of Education, Health, and Nursing Arts Professionals (SEHNAP), (1960- 1983) includes some material created during the deanship of Walter A. Anderson. However the majority of the files were created under the deanship of Daniel E. Griffiths.
On March 3, 1965 Daniel E. Griffiths was appointed Dean of the School of Education, after having served as Associate Dean for four years (1961-1965). Griffiths was Dean of the School of Education and then SEHNAP for eighteen years, through the political, economic, and social upheavals of the 1960s through the early 1980s. In these years the School of Education faced enrollment crises and budget problems. In meeting these challenges, Griffiths combined his background as a specialist in educational administration and administrative theory with the conviction that the School must adapt itself to modern society in order to serve the emerging and future needs of the community.
Daniel Griffiths received his B.Ed. in 1940 at Central Connecticut State College, after which he taught high school science and mathematics in Bristol, Connecticut. Griffiths went on to earn his M.Ed. in 1949 at the University of New Hampshire, and then his Ph.D. in 1952 at Yale University. From 1952-1955, Griffiths served as Project Associate, then Professor and Director of the Administrative Seminar Project at the New York State College for Teachers at Albany. From 1955-1956, Griffiths worked with the New York State Department of Education as Director of Cooperative Development of Public School Administration and as Associate Coordinator of Educational Research. From 1956-1959, Griffiths served in several capacities at Teachers College of Columbia University. From 1956-1961, Griffiths was associate and then full professor. Additionally, he held numerous directorships within the college. In 1961, Griffiths became Associate Dean of the School of Education at NYU.
During his deanship, Griffiths consistently elucidated what he believed to be some of the problems and solutions of the contemporary educational systems. In 1970, among the failures of the educational system, Griffiths noted what he called the mass-production concept of education, the domination of society by large and complex organizations, wherein emphasis was placed on the functioning of large bureaucracies rather than individual capabilities, the depersonalization of society, and prolonged infantilism of the individual. He believed that the latter stemmed from an unnecessarily long educational process based on an antiquated rural harvest cycle. Among the solutions that Griffiths proposed was rigorous training for students of poor families to provide them some of the same educational opportunities as those enjoyed by students of the middle classes. In 1979 Griffiths indicated the need for the School of Education to continue to tailor itself to serving the community through the addition of programs such as gerontology, education in non-school contexts, technology, and computers.
Dean Griffiths introduced over thirty-nine new programs to the School of Education, which was renamed the School of Education, Health and Nursing Arts Professionals in 1974. Notable programs include the American Poverty Experience (APEX) program that was established in 1967, which trained young men from the slums to be educators and work for their communities. In 1970, Griffiths introduced an initially controversial Masters and Ph.D degrees-granting Human Sexuality Program.
Acknowledged as Griffiths' most important contribution to the field of education was his introduction of the research professor who would use social science theory to improve education at the administrative and teaching levels alongside the more traditional practitioner professor who taught with the use of practical examples. Griffiths' theories for the improvement of education and his teaching methods greatly strengthened the academic and research dimension of the NYU School of Education, and won him recognition in the national and international community. Griffiths gave over two hundred lectures and workshops both domestically and abroad, and his methods and theories have been adopted widely. Griffiths also played a key role in the formation of the University Council for Educational Administration (UCEA), an organization for the improvement of educational administration and the development of educational leaders. The UCEA is now a consortium of 70 research universities in Canada and in the United States.
Dean Griffiths' articles appeared in over seventy journals. He edited and authored eleven books including Administrative Theory (1965) and The Dilemma of Deanship (1979). Additionally Griffiths chaired the editorial board of the Education Quarterly, which was published from 1969 until 1983.
Griffiths retired from NYU in 1983. In recognition of his commitment to research and development, the Griffiths Research Award was established in 1983. It is awarded annually to single or collaborating faculty members whose research contributes to professional practice or knowledge in his or her field. Daniel Griffiths died on October 5, 1995.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files included in the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted.
Provenance
Office of the Dean of the School of Education, Daniel E. Griffiths
Financial records; New York (N.Y.).; School administrators -- Training of -- United States.; School management and organization |z United States.; Education |z United States |x Aims and Objectives.; Teachers |x Selection and appointment |z New York (State) |z New York.; Case files.; Manuscripts; Biographical files.; Correspondence.; Minutes (administrative records); School management and organization.; School superintendents and principals, Rating of.; School superintedents and principals.; School personnel management.; University Council for Educational Administration; New York University; Griffiths, Daniel Edward, 1917-; Anderson, Walter Alexander
- Griffiths Container List
  - By Laws - SEHNAP, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058 171 5
  - Faculty Benefits, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Catering, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Film Library, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Grievance, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - NYU Financial Reports, 1969-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Commission on Language & Literacy, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Japan, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Henrietta Fleck Room, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - HEOP, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - High School of the Humanities, 1985-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Helbein Scholars, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Great Teacher Award, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Government Relations, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Office of Graduate Admissions, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - New York Alliance, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - New York Alliance - Teaching the 3 R's, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Puerto Rico Commencement, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Parents Day, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Presidential Fellows, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - NYU Contributions to Regional Economy, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Placement, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Puerto Rico Budget, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Program Termination Policies & Procedure, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Public Affairs, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Regents Commission's Regional Conference, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Board of Regents, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Future's Report, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Commission on Women's Studies, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Teacher Supply & Demand Survey, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Teaching Performance Center, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Thailand, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058 172 3
  - Taiwan, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lillian Pizzoli, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - NYU Tenure, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Summer Sessions, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Soloman Estate, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - State of the School, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - State of the School, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - State of the School, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Annual Report to the President (Draft - Working Papers), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Religious Education & Public Policy Welcome Remarka, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Review of Educational Research Methods for Intergrative Review, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Conference on Declining Enrollment, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Exploratory College in the Profession at NYU - European Model (draft), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Division of Education: Comments on Final Report of Planning Committee, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058 173 1
  - GSO Education Fair, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Para Educator Center, Dedication Ceremony Remarks, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Education Associates - Alumni Association, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Newman Literacy Award Presentation (Hebrew Culture Fund), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - DEG Alumni Speech, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Students - NYU Education, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Speech - Students - NYU Education (Prof. Gorn's Class), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bulletin Reorganization & Redesign, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bulletin Covers, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bd. of Education for the Handicapped, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Long Range Planning Committee of Division of Education, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Academic Planning Commission, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - NYU Summer Musical Theater Workshop, 1982-1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - State of the School - Address to the Faculty, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Report to the Faculty, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - State of the School, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - State of the School, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - State of the School, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Annual Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Annual Reports, Division of Education, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Annual Report, Division of Health, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Annual Report, Division of Nursing, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Annual Report, Division of Arts and Arts Professions, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Annual Report, Study Outside Normal Schedule, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Annual Report, Sponsored Programs and Research, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Annual Report, Arts Division, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Annual Report, Health Division, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Annual Report, Center for the Study of Food Service Management, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Annual Report, Nursing Division, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Annual Report, Education Division, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Recruitment, Undergraduate Student Marketing Plan, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058 174 9
  - Handbook for Advisors of Students, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Resume of Alumni Federation Services to the Education Alumni Assoc. Fund, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Special Report for Presentation to Chancellor Heald, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Federal Agency Contact Officials, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - The Report of the President, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - UCEA - Directory of Minority Group Members, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Reconnections fo Learning, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Recruitment, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058 175 6
  - Annual Report to the President, 1978-79 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report to the President (Draft), 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report to the President (Correspondence), 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Annual Report to the President, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Board of Education (Correspondence Courses), 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Agnew Lecture Remarks, 1977-1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Doctoral Case Study Potential, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - CCEA (Commonwealth Council for Educational Administration), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Collapse of Concensus - Commencement Rain Plan Speech, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Anniversary - NYU 150th, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Steering Committee Report Ratings of SEHNAP Doctoral Programs, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Steering Committee Report Ratings of SEHNAP Doctoral Programs (Draft), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Consultant's Information Sheet, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Guide for Consultants Visits, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Events in the Review of Doctoral Program: Self-Evaluation, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - General Selection of Merrifield, Steering Committee Report, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Consultants, Self-Evaluation List, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Accounting System Requirements, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058 176 4
  - AERA Institutional Affiliates, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Professor Perry Meisel Spencer Foundation Grant, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Spencer Review Meeting, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Professor Priscilla J. Hambrick - Spencer Foundation Grant, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Professor Annick Mansfield - Spencer Foundation Grant, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Professor Rochelle Kern-Daniels - Spencer Foundation Grant, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Professor Stephen Stump - Development: A Study of Career Decision Proc., 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Spencer Foundation Grant - D. E. Griffiths, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Spencer Foundation Grant to the Young Scholars - NYU, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Spencer Foundation Grant Reviewing Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Spencer Foundation Grant Asst. Prof. Robert Q. Young, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Spencer Foundation Grant Asst. Prof. Michael Brennan, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Spencer Foundation Grant Asst. Prof. Rochelle Kern-Daniels, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Spencer Foundation Grant Prof. Carolyn Soarni / Sabbatical Leave, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Spencer Foundation Grant Asst. Prof. Robert Thatcher, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Final Reports - Spencer, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Spencer Forms, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Dr. Glen Conroy - Spencer Foundation Grant, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Wayne Hreski - Ed. Psychology - Spencer, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Giaquinta, Joe, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Spencer Recipients, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Spencer Proposals - Rejected, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Spencer Proposals - Rejected, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058 177 2
  - Spencer Foundation, 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Association, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Awards Reception, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Elmer E. Baker, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Dept. of Bilingual Education, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bilingual Deans Grant Fund, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bilingual Vocational Instruction Training Program, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Frank Bloomfield, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Budget Advisory Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Budget & Fund Transfers (all departments), 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Budget Material, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Pat Carey, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Dean Gabriel Carras, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Center for the Study of Human Relations, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Central Administration, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Challenge Fund, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Curriculum Challenge Fund, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Commission on Independent Colleges & Universities, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Commencement, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Deafness Center, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Deans Group Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Dept. of Communication Arts and Sciences, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Pat Yacobbacci, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058 178 0
  - Dept. of Counselor Education, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Dept. of Dance and Dance Education, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Dept. of Curriculum and Instruction, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - State Dept. of Education, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Department of Educational Psychology, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Department of Health Education, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Department of Hebrew Studies, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Department of Home Economics, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Department of Music and Music Education, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Department of Occupational Therapy, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Department of Organizational and Administrative Studies, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Department of Physical Therapy, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Department of Prosthetics and Orthetics, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Department of Recreation and Leisure Studies, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Department of Physical Education, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Department of Rehabilitation Counseling, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Department of Technology and Industrial Education, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Development Projects, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Development Office (Starr, McClosky, Walker), 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Division of Art, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Division of Education (Prof. Lonsdale), 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Division of Health (Prof. Livingston), 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Division of Nursing (Dr. McGriff), 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Division Head Meetings, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Education Program Standing Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Ethics (AERA) & (SIG), 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Faculty Meetings SEHNAP, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Faculty / Personnel Recruitment, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Family Education Rights and Privacy Act, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Federal Budget Material, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Federal Regulations, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - A21, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - AACTE, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - AAHE, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous Books, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - History of Education Quarterly, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Study of the Educational System of Puerto Rico, Volumes I-II, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - General Findings and Recommendations, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Academic Computing Committee, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058 179 8
  - Admissions, Undergraduate Reports, 1973-1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Affirmative Action Report Discussed with Deans, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Alumni College, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Association, 1976-1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Association, Board of Directors, 1975-1983 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Federation, 1968-1983 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Anniversaries, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Arts Recognition and Talent Search - ETS Competition, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Attrition Reports, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Bilingual Scholarships - Juventud Espanola, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Calendar: 4-Day Summer Week, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Camp Ramapo, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Choral Arts Society, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Commencement, 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Commencement Rain Plans, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Comparative Urban Problems - course proposal competition, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Counseling Services, 1976-1982 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Deafness Research and Training Center, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Deafness Research and Training Center, National Advisory Board, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058 180 6
  - Deans Development Fund, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Dissertation Service, Office of Graduate Studies Report, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Education Quarterly, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - England, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Edelman, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Educational Administration Quarterly, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Enrollment Reports, 1980-1983 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Financial Aid and Financial Aid Survey, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Financial Exigency at NYU, principles and guidelines, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Financial Emergency, Report of NYU Task Force, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Founders Day, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Gifts and Pledges, Comparison Reports, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Glazer, Judith, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Gordon, Cyrus, DEG's Introduction of, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Graduate Cohort Study, MA, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04058 181 4
  - Graduate Follow Up and Cohort Study and Questionnaire, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Undergraduate Follow Up Survey, 1980-1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Studies, Office of, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Hebrew and Judaic Studies, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Helena Rubinstein Foundation, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 6)